<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud-functions on Guillaume Laforge</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/tags/cloud-functions/</link><description>Recent content in cloud-functions on Guillaume Laforge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 15:53:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glaforge.github.io/tags/cloud-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monitoring Website Changes with Workflows Cloud Functions and Sendgrid</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/monitoring-website-change-wwith-workflows-cloud-functions-and-sendgrid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 15:53:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/monitoring-website-change-wwith-workflows-cloud-functions-and-sendgrid/</guid><description>Every year in France, around mid-September, there&amp;rsquo;s a special weekend where everyone can visit some famous places, usually closed the rest of the year. That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Journée du Patrimoine&amp;rdquo;. For example, you can visit places like the Elysée Palace or the Matignon Palace, if you want to see where the French president, or the French prime minister work. However, for some of those places, it&amp;rsquo;s tricky to register online to book a slot, as there&amp;rsquo;s always a high demand for them.</description></item><item><title>Skyrocketing Micronaut Microservices Into Google Cloud</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/talks/skyrocketing-micronaut-microservices-into-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 14:27:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/talks/skyrocketing-micronaut-microservices-into-google-cloud/</guid><description>Instead of spending too much time on infrastructure, take advantage of readily available serverless solutions. Focus on your Micronaut code, and deploy it rapidly as a function, an application, or within a container, on Google Cloud Platform, with Cloud Functions, App Engine, or Cloud Run.
In this presentation, you’ll discover the options you have to deploy your Micronaut applications and services on Google Cloud. With Micronaut Launch, it’s easy to get started with a template project, and with a few tweaks, you can then push your code to production.</description></item></channel></rss>