<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>microservices on Guillaume Laforge</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/tags/microservices/</link><description>Recent content in microservices on Guillaume Laforge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 21:56:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glaforge.github.io/tags/microservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Choreography vs Orchestration in Microservices and Best Practices</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/talks/choreography-vs-orchestration-in-microservices-and-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 21:56:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/talks/choreography-vs-orchestration-in-microservices-and-best-practices/</guid><description>We went from a single monolith to a set of microservices that are small, lightweight, and easy to implement. Microservices enable reusability, make it easier to change and scale apps on demand but they also introduce new problems. How do microservices interact with each other toward a common goal? How do you figure out what went wrong when a business process composed of several microservices fails? Should there be a central orchestrator controlling all interactions between services or should each service work independently, in a loosely coupled way, and only interact through shared events?</description></item><item><title>Skyrocketing Micronaut Microservices Into Google Cloud</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/talks/skyrocketing-micronaut-microservices-into-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 14:27:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/talks/skyrocketing-micronaut-microservices-into-google-cloud/</guid><description>Instead of spending too much time on infrastructure, take advantage of readily available serverless solutions. Focus on your Micronaut code, and deploy it rapidly as a function, an application, or within a container, on Google Cloud Platform, with Cloud Functions, App Engine, or Cloud Run.
In this presentation, you’ll discover the options you have to deploy your Micronaut applications and services on Google Cloud. With Micronaut Launch, it’s easy to get started with a template project, and with a few tweaks, you can then push your code to production.</description></item></channel></rss>