<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Guillaume Laforge</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Guillaume Laforge</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 18:10:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glaforge.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Calculating your potential reach on Mastodon with Google Cloud Workflows orchestrating the Mastodon APIs</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/calculating-your-potential-reach-on-mastodon-with-google-cloud-workflows-orchestrating-the-mastodon-apis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 18:10:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/calculating-your-potential-reach-on-mastodon-with-google-cloud-workflows-orchestrating-the-mastodon-apis/</guid><description>With the turmoil around Twitter, like many, I’ve decided to look into Mastodon. My friend Geert is running his own Mastodon server, and welcomed me on his instance at: uwyn.net/@glaforge.
With Twitter, you can access your analytics to know how your tweets are doing, how many views you’re getting. Working in developer relations, it’s always interesting to get some insights into those numbers to figure out if what you’re sharing is interesting for your community.</description></item><item><title>Turning a Website Into a Desktop Application</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/turning-a-website-into-a-desktop-application/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 12:47:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/turning-a-website-into-a-desktop-application/</guid><description>Probably like most of you, my dear readers, I have too many browser windows open, with tons of tabs for each window. But there are always apps I come back to very often, like my email (professional &amp;amp; personal), my calendar, my chat app, or even social media sites like Mastodon or Twitter. You can switch from window to window with CTRL/CMD-Tab, but you also have to move between tabs potentially.</description></item><item><title>APIs, we have a Problem JSON</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/apis-we-have-a-problem-json/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 13:37:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/apis-we-have-a-problem-json/</guid><description>When designing a web API, not only do you have to think about the happy path when everything is alright, but you also have to handle all the error cases: Is the payload received correct? Is there a typo in a field? Do you need more context about the problem that occured?
There’s only a limited set of status codes that can convey the kind of error you’re getting, but sometimes you need to explain more clearly what the error is about.</description></item><item><title>Workflows Tips and Tricks</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/workflows-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:15:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/workflows-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>Here are some general tips and tricks that we found useful as we used Google Cloud Workflows:
Avoid hard-coding URLs Since Workflows is all about calling APIs and service URLs, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have some clean way to handle those URLs. You can hard-code them in your workflow definition, but the problem is that your workflow can become harder to maintain. In particular, what happens when you work with multiple environments?</description></item><item><title>Retrieve YouTube views count with youtubeDL, JQ, and a Docker container</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/retrieve-youtube-views-count-with-youtubedl-jq-and-a-docker-container/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 14:53:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/retrieve-youtube-views-count-with-youtubedl-jq-and-a-docker-container/</guid><description>I wanted to track the number of views, and also likes, of some YouTube videos I was featured in. For example, when I present a talk at a conference, often the video becomes available at a later time, and I&amp;rsquo;m not the owner of the channel or video. At first, I wanted to use the YouTube Data API, but I had the impression that I could only see the stats of videos or channels I own, however I think I might be wrong, and should probably revisit this approach later on.</description></item><item><title>Build Deploy Java 17 Apps on Cloud Run With Cloud Native Buildpacks on Temurin</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/build-deploy-java-17-apps-on-cloud-run-with-cloud-native-buildpacks-on-temurin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 11:33:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/build-deploy-java-17-apps-on-cloud-run-with-cloud-native-buildpacks-on-temurin/</guid><description>In this article, let&amp;rsquo;s revisit the topic of deploying Java apps on Cloud Run. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;ll deploy a Micronaut app, written with Java 17, and built with Gradle.
With a custom Dockerfile On Cloud Run, you deploy containerised applications, so you have to decide the way you want to build a container for your application. In a previous article, I showed an example of using your own Dockerfile, which would look as follows with an OpenJDK 17, and enabling preview features of the language:</description></item><item><title>A Cloud Run service in Go calling a Workflows callback endpoint</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/a-cloud-run-service-in-go-calling-a-workflows-callback-endpoint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 16:02:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/a-cloud-run-service-in-go-calling-a-workflows-callback-endpoint/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s all Richard Seroter&amp;rsquo;s fault, I ended up dabbling with Golang! We were chatting about a use case using Google Cloud Workflows and a Cloud Run service implemented in Go. So it was the occasion to play a bit with Go. Well, I still don&amp;rsquo;t like error handling&amp;hellip; But let&amp;rsquo;s rewind the story a bit!
Workflows is a fully-managed service/API orchestrator on Google Cloud. You can create some advanced business workflows using YAML syntax.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Website Changes with Workflows Cloud Functions and Sendgrid</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/monitoring-website-change-wwith-workflows-cloud-functions-and-sendgrid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 15:53:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/monitoring-website-change-wwith-workflows-cloud-functions-and-sendgrid/</guid><description>Every year in France, around mid-September, there&amp;rsquo;s a special weekend where everyone can visit some famous places, usually closed the rest of the year. That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Journée du Patrimoine&amp;rdquo;. For example, you can visit places like the Elysée Palace or the Matignon Palace, if you want to see where the French president, or the French prime minister work. However, for some of those places, it&amp;rsquo;s tricky to register online to book a slot, as there&amp;rsquo;s always a high demand for them.</description></item><item><title>Schedule a Workflow Execution</title><link>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/schedule-a-workflow-execution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 17:06:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://glaforge.github.io/posts/schedule-a-workflow-execution/</guid><description>There are different ways to launch the execution of a workflow. In previous articles, we mentioned that you can use the gcloud command-line tool to create an execution, you can also use the various client libraries to invoke Workflows, or use the REST API. A workflow itself can also invoke other workflows!
But today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to tell you how to schedule the execution of a workflow. For that purpose, we&amp;rsquo;ll take advantage of Cloud Scheduler.</description></item></channel></rss>